Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
THE YEAR IS 2016 A.D.
THE THING THAT PEOPLE HAD LOST
IN OTHER WORDS, THE INSTRUMENTALITY
OF SOULS WAS STILL ONGOING
HOWEVER, THERE IS FAR TOO LITTLE TIME LEFT
TO MAKE MENTION OF IT ALL
THEREFORE, NOW, WE WILL TAKE
THE BOY NAMED SHINJI IKARI
AND TELL THE STORY OF THE
INSTRUMENTALITY OF HIS SOUL
IN THE CASE OF SHINJI IKARI
FEAR
Of ceasing to exist.
But considering the way I am,
I don't think I need to exist.
Why not?
Because I'm not needed.
I'm an unwanted child after all.
No one cares about what happens to me!
You're running away by thinking
that it doesn't matter.
You're afraid of failure, aren't you?
You're afraid that people won't
love you, aren't you?
You're afraid of seeing how
weak you are, aren't you?
But that's exactly how you are too, Miss Misato!
That's right, we're all the same.
There's a piece of our hearts missing.
That's what we're afraid of.
It makes us insecure.
That's why we're all trying
to become one right now.
We're trying to make up for it with each other.
That is the Instrumentality Project.
Humans cannot live unless they are in groups.
Humans cannot live alone.
Even though there is only one of you.
That's why you suffer.
That's why you feel lonely.
That's why you want to meld your body
and soul with someone else's.
You want to become one.
Humans are made of weak and fragile stuff.
The body and soul are also made
of weak and fragile stuff.
That is why we must complement
one another through instrumentality.
"WHY?"
Because we cannot live otherwise.
"REALLY?"
What are you alive for?
"I DON'T KNOW"
Maybe I'm living because
I want to figure that out.
Who are you living for?
For myself, of course.
For myself, I think.
"REALLY?"
Are you happy to be alive?
I don't know.
Of course, I'm happy!
Are you happy to be alive?
I only want to do what I enjoy doing.
Do you hate feeling lonely?
I don't like it.
Do you hate suffering?
Is that why you run away?
That's right.
What's wrong with running away
from the things you don't like?!
Exit
I shouldn't run away!
Why mustn't you run away?
Because running away is painful.
Even though you're running away
from something painful?
It was painful.
If you know it's going to be painful,
then what does it matter?
Yes, you can run away if it's painful.
If you really hate it, you can run away.
But I don't want to! I don't want
to run away anymore!
That's right, it's wrong to run away.
That's because you feel that it's
more painful to just run away.
Play
Messages
Because you learned how painful
it is to run away.
That's why you don't want to run away, isn't it?
Because if I run away, no one will respect me.
Don't forsake me.
Please, don't forsake me!
Quietly obeying what other
people tell him to do,
maybe that's his survival mechanism.
That's right! Because if I don't,
I'll be abandoned again.
You're afraid of being hurt, aren't you?
It's just what you've made
yourself believe, isn't it?
Shinji, you're not the only one who's hurting.
You're not the only one
goin' through tough times.
You only believe that,
because it's easier to think that.
Shut up! That has nothing to do with this!
No one cares what happens to me!
You're always so quick to
dismiss your self-worth.
Because I have nothing.
There you go again, making yourself
believe that you're worthless!
Because if you believe that and
do nothing, you won't be hurt.
You sustain your identity with the praise
you receive from people.
No one will accept me.
You've made yourself believe that.
That's why I have to pilot the Eva.
You've made yourself believe that
you are worthless to start with.
That's what I have to do!
That's not true.
You've probably just made
yourself believe that.
No, I am worthless.
I have nothing to be proud of.
That's why you pilot the Eva.
By piloting the Eva, I can be me.
I had nothing before I started piloting the Eva.
I'm allowed to be here, because I pilot the Eva.
I have nothing else.
Because I have nothing else.
I have nothing, nothing at all.
"THAT MAKES MY LIFE WORTH SOMETHING"
Nothing.
"...SO"
I hate myself.
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you so much!
Man, I just hate you!
I hate who you are.
I'm sorry, I hate you.
I hate you.
I do hate you.
I hate who you are.
I hate the person you are.
I just hate you!
See? Everyone thinks so.
Transfer Application
Shinji Ikari
I know that's what they think.
You're just making yourself believe that.
No! Because I hate myself!
So, you've made yourself believe that
everyone else thinks so too.
I hate you!
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you so much!
But they still praise me.
They'll praise me if I pilot the Eva.
People praised me.
"THAT'S WHY I'M HAPPY"
"BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE ME HAPPY"
Which way do you really feel?
I don't know.
No, both ways are real.
And that's why you pilot the Eva, isn't it?
Because right now, the Eva is all I have.
Because otherwise, you can't
maintain your identity.
It's true, Eva Unit 01 is a part of who you are.
But if you keep clinging to the Eva,
the Eva itself will become you.
The Eva itself will become all you are.
The real you will cease to exist.
I don't care!
I never had anything to begin with anyway!
Even the cello lessons I used to take
all came to nothing.
That's because you never took the
initiative to make something of it!
But I can pilot the Eva now!
And eventually, you won't be able
to do anything without the Eva.
Like me.
"WHY DO YOU PILOT THE EVA?"
Because that is all I have.
FINAL EPISODE
THE BEAST THAT
SHOUTED LOVE
AT THE HEART
OF THE WORLD
Rain...
A depressing mood...
It's like the mood I'm in.
I don't like it.
Sunset...
Vanishing life...
My wish...
I don't like it.
Morning...
The start of today...
The start of an unpleasant day...
I don't like it.
The blue sky...
Something warm...
Something I'm not used to...
Something frightening...
Something that's not needed...
I don't like it.
Everyone! I just hate everyone!
What do you desire?
"ARE YOU AFRAID OF BEING INSECURE?"
What do you want?
"DO YOU WANT PEACE OF MIND?"
What do you seek?
"DON'T HATE ME!"
Don't hate me!
What I'm afraid of is...
REJECTION
What I want is...
TO CONNECT AND TO BE RECOGNIZED
Is it okay if I stick around?
Is it okay if I stay here?
Do you love me?
"DO YOU LOVE"
"YOUR MOTHER?"
Do you want to go to your mom?
No, I don't want to.
Aren't you going to go to your father?
Why not?
BECAUSE I'M AFRAID
Because I'm afraid he'll hate me.
Because I might cease to be me.
"SO?"
What do you desire?
A RESOLUTION TO THE INSECURITY
What do you seek?
A RESOLUTION TO THE LONELINESS
You're not happy, are you?
I want something before that.
I want to be worth something.
Worth enough so no one will abandon me,
so they'll care about me.
"I WANT TO BE WORTH SOMETHING"
Only you can find your own worth.
THAT'S WHY YOU PILOT THE EVA
I'm worthless.
My life isn't worth enough to live.
Then, what are you?
Then, what am I?
What am I?!
This is...
Me!
It's the form of me that I show to others.
It's the symbol that is me.
So is this, and this and this!
SHINJI IKARI
They're all just things that represent me.
They're all merely what other people
recognize as me.
Then, what am I?
"WHERE DO I EXIST?"
Is this me?
The real me?
The false me?
You are you.
The only thing is, there's a distinct
difference between that
and the actual scope of who you are.
That's right.
My clothes...
My shoes...
My room...
These things are a part of me.
The things that are linked together
through your consciousness.
The thing that I feel to be me, is me.
I am nothing more than myself then.
But I don't understand me.
Where do I exist?
What am I?
What am I?!
THAT IS WHY I
WISH FOR MY
SOUL TO BE
CLOSED OFF
No one understands anything about me!
What are you, stupid?! Of course,
no one understands!
No one could possibly understand
anything about you!
The only person who can sympathize
with you and understand you, is you.
So, be good to yourself.
But there's no me! I don't understand!
There's no way I can be good to that!
"YOU'RE INSECURE"
In the end, you're insecure.
The way you are now...
The people around you now...
The environment that surrounds you now...
None of these things will last forever.
Time will keep passing for you.
Your world is made up of continual change.
But above all, it's all up to your heart and mind.
You can change the world at any time.
What is this?
A world with nothing in it?
A world with nobody in it?
A world of freedom.
Freedom?
It's a world of freedom, where there's
nothing restricting you.
This is freedom?
Yes, a world of freedom.
But in exchange, there's nothing.
As long as I don't think of anything?
Yes, as long as you don't think of anything.
But I don't know what I should do.
You're insecure, aren't you?
You don't have an image of yourself, do you?
It's all just too vague.
A world where there is nothing
solid enough to grab onto...
THAT IS FREEDOM
A world you can do anything you want with...
But you're insecure, aren't you?
Do you not know what you should do?
What should I do?
I will give you a restriction.
There, now you have heaven and earth.
But now, you've lost one aspect of your freedom.
You must stand on the ground.
But you feel more secure.
Because a small weight has been
lifted from your mind.
And you try walking.
That is of your own will.
This is my will?
A ground exists in this world,
and that is the world you live in.
But you can move around in it freely.
If you wanted to, you could even change
the position of the world.
And the position of the world
never stays still either.
It changes, along with the passage of time.
You yourself can change as well.
Because what shapes you is your own mind
and the world around you.
For, this is your world.
It's the form of reality that you perceive.
"THAT IS REALITY"
This is...
A space with nothing in it.
A world with nothing in it.
A world that has nothing else in it, except me.
I'm losing my grasp on who I am.
I feel like I'm disappearing.
The existence that is me is vanishing.
"WHY?"
Because you are the only one here.
Because I'm the only one?
Because without the existence of
things other than yourself,
you cannot know your own shape.
My own shape?
"MY IMAGE OF ME?"
Yes, you know your own shape through
seeing how other people are shaped.
By looking at the barrier between you
and other people,
you visualize your own shape.
You cannot see yourself unless
there are other people.
I can exist because there are
other people around!
If I'm alone, I'll always be alone,
no matter how far I go with it!
All the world would just be me!
By recognizing the differences
between yourself and others,
you shape who you are.
The very first other person is your mother.
Your mother is a person separate from you.
Right, I'm me.
But it's also certain that the other people
shape my mind as well!
That's right, Shinji Ikari.
Did you finally figure that out, stupid Shinji?!
So, you're finally awake, stupid Shinji.
Oh, it's just you, Asuka.
JUST me?! I come over here every morning
to make sure that YOU aren't late to school,
and those are the words of gratitude
you offer to your childhood friend?!
Yeah, thanks.
So let me sleep for a little longer.
What kind of spoiled attitude is that?!
Darn it, hurry up and get up!
Pervert! Idiot! Letch! I can't believe you!
I can't help it! It's morning!
Oh, that Shinji.
Asuka's being so nice, coming to get him.
He's just hopeless.
Yes, Dear.
You too! Stop burying your nose in that
newspaper and get ready to go.
Yes, Dear.
Honestly, a grown man and you're
no different than Shinji.
Are you all ready to go?
Yes, any time!
I'm the one who gets scolded by
Professor Fuyutsuki
when we're late to meetings, you know.
You're just that popular.
Don't be silly! Please hurry up and get dressed!
Yes, Dear.
South Pole Showa Base Opening Its Doors to visitors First African-American Female President
I know, Yui.
Come on, hurry up!
Yeah, I know!
You're such a pain, Asuka!
What did you say?!
Well, Mrs. Ikari, see you later!
See you later.
Okay, I'll see you later!
Come on, Dear! When are you going
to put that newspaper down?!
Yes, I know, Yui.
I heard there's a transfer student
coming in today.
Well, by next year, they'll have transferred
the capital here after all.
There's going to be more
and more people coming.
That's true. I wonder what she's like?
I hope she's cute.
Oh, I'm late! I'm late!
It'd be pretty bad if I'm late
on my first day, right?!
Sorry about that! I was seriously in a hurry!
Really sorry about that!
What are you, stupid?
What?! So, did you see them?
That girl's panties?
I didn't really see them, just a little flash.
You sure are a lucky bastard!
And the day's just started!
What's the big idea, Class Rep?!
And what about you, Suzuhara?!
What kind of stupid talk is this
to start the morning off with?!
Come on, hurry up and go change
the water in the flower vase!
It's your week, isn't it?!
Man, you're such a pain!
What did you say?!
He's the type who's going to
end up getting whipped.
So are you.
Why am I the type that's going
to end up getting whipped?
What? I call it like I see it.
Why?!
Just look at yourself!
That's just because you never shut up!
Man, it's so peaceful.
Oh, be quiet, stupid Shinji!
Hey, it's Miss Misato!
Miss Misato's just awesome!
What's with that stupid trio?! They're so dumb!
Rise! Bow!
Be seated!
Rejoice, boys!
Let me introduce the much-rumored
transfer student!
I'm Rei Ayanami, nice to meet you.
You! You're the panty-peeker
from this morning!
Hey! That's not fair!
You're the one who flashed them at Shinji!
Who are you?! Leaping to his defense like that?!
What are you, an item?!
Pull Back
We're just childhood friends! You annoying brat!
Hey, we're in the middle of class!
Please be quiet!
Come on, this sounds like fun.
I want to know too.
Please continue.
I get it, this is also a possible world.
One possibility that's in me.
The me right now is not exactly who I am.
All sorts of me's are possible.
That's right. A me that's not
an Eva pilot is possible too.
When you think of it that way,
this world of reality isn't so bad.
The world of reality might not be so bad.
But I hate myself.
It's you that perceives reality
as bad and unpleasant.
It's you who's mistaken reality for the truth.
Your perspective on reality and the
importance you place on reality,
the slightest difference in these things will
greatly change the world inside your mind.
There are as many truths as there are people.
But there is only one truth for you.
One made from your narrow
perception of the world
and from information that was
altered to protect yourself,
a warped truth.
Well, one person's perception of the world's
bound to be tiny anyway.
But people only have that tiny ruler
to measure their surroundings with.
And you only try to see things through
the truths that other people have given you.
On sunny days, you feel good.
On rainy days, you feel down.
Once you've been taught that, you make yourself
believe that's how you should feel.
Even though pleasant things
can happen on rainy days too.
It's a delicate thing that can be
completely transformed
just by how you perceive something.
The truth within people, that is.
That's about how solid the truth is for humans.
Though, that's what also makes people
seek a deeper truth.
You are merely not used to
being loved by other people.
So there's no need for you to constantly care
about what other people think of you.
But doesn't everybody hate me?
What are you, stupid?!
You're just making yourself
believe that, that's all!
But I hate myself.
Anyone who hates himself can't
come to love and trust others.
I'm a gutless, hypocritical, wimpy coward.
See? If you understand yourself,
you can be kind.
I hate myself.
But maybe I can learn to love myself.
Maybe it's okay for me to be here!
That's right! I'm me, nothing more, nothing less!
I'm me.
I want to be me!
I want to be here!
And it's okay for me to be here!
Congratulations!
Congrats!
Thank you.
TO MY FATHER, THANK YOU.
TO MY MOTHER, FAREWELL.
AND TO ALL THE CHILDREN...
CONGRATULATIONS!